We have seen loops that include conditional
expressions, such as an if statement, and
how to use an if statement to break or skip
over part of a loop.
Let’s take this concept one step further
and see a loop that includes a compound conditional
statement, which is a statement with two or
more conditions.
To demonstrate this use of a compound conditional
statement, we will modify the code example
we used for the continue statement.
In this version of the file, 227-compound,
we still have four coins in a coins tuple
on line 1, and we still have a for loop that
starts on line 3.
Within the loop, each coin is examined, and
if the coin is platinum, a player is moved
to the next level.
However, on line 2, we have a new Boolean
variable for a scepter, and the test value
is set to True.
In the game flow, one must have the scepter
and the platinum coin to move to the next
level.
We could add another if statement to accommodate
this need.
Still, a more efficient idea would be to add
this criterion to the existing if statement
and make that if statement a compound conditional
statement.
I will add, to the if statement on line 5,
and that scepter equals True.
This code should return the special message
for the platinum coin since the scepter variable
is set to True.
I will run this code, and we see the special
print statement for the platinum coin.
If, on line 2, I change the scepter variable
to False and then rerun the code, the special
statement for the platinum coin does not print
because both conditions in the if statement
with the and operator are not true.
Using a compound conditional operator saves
time as it prevents one from having to run
multiple if statements to get the same results
from code.
We have reached the end of this topic, so
it’s time for another code analysis.
Take a look at this 227-analyze code.
Then, go to your workbook and work through
the Review 2.7 project, as there are two questions
to answer about this code.
I will reveal the answers to those questions
in the next video.
As always, if you can type this code out and
run through its logic while building the code,
all the better.